

# Since I was a little kid...

... I've been fascinated about technology and the built environment. While building the biggest LEGO-cities in my parents' garage, my granddad taught me how to connect light bulbs with batteries.

15 years later, I'm combining my passion for tech and the city as a researcher at Eindhoven University of Technology. I've got a rock-solid motivation to create hyperconnected buildings and cities and make technology available for everyone.

# Education

2020 HPI, University of Potsdam

Linked Data Engineering

2019 **PTV VISSIM** 

Basic course & Dynamic Traffic Assignment

2019 Aveta Business Institute

LSSWB Lean Six Sigma White Belt

2017 - 2019 Eindhoven University of Technology

MSc. Construction Management & Engineering

Cum Laude (8.6/10)

2018 Harvard University

CitiesX: The Past, Present and Future City Life (9.4/10)

2015 **ESA** 

Conflict management, Feedback, Time management and Meeting techniques

2015 Kenneth Smit

Certificate of Distinction: Expert in Acquisitions

2013 - 2017 Eindhoven University of Technology

BSc. Architecture, Building and Planning

2007 - 2013 Commanderij College Sleutelbosch

VWO, Nature & Technology and Nature & Health

# Experience

#### 2021 TIAS Business School

Visiting Lecturer Executive Master of Real Estate (MRE)

## 2019 - now Eindhoven University of Technology

PhD Candidate in SmartTWO, a KPN+TU/e collaboration

#### 2019 **Sweco**

Graduate Intern Mobility and Data

### 2017 - 2019 Eindhoven University of Technology

Teaching Assistant Real-Estate Transformation

#### 2011 - 2018 Albert Heijn

Team Leader

#### 2016 - 2017 **VIRTUe**

Designing and building a smart and sustainable house at the Solar Decathlon 2018 in Dubai Starred in Reuters, RTLZ, AD, ED, Financieel Dagblad, ...

#### 2015 - 2016 **KIVI**

Board Member 'Bouw'

### 2015 - 2016 CHEOPS, Study Association

Full Time Board Member, Professional Relations

#### 2015 - 2016 Archilign

Junior Architectural Designer

## Research interests

Semantic web technologies
Digitalization in the built environment
Occupant-centric building performance
Semantic digital twins
Ontology development
Data federation and web applications
Open BIM
Sensors and IoT

## **Publications**

**Donkers, A.**, De Vries, B. & Yang, D. (2022). Creating Occupant-Centered Digital Twins Using the Occupant Feedback Ontology Implemented in a Smartwatch App. Semantic Web for Industrial Engineering: Research and Applications. Semantic Web Journal. IOS Press.

**Donkers, A.**, Van Midden, J. & Yang, D. (2022). Parallel Intelligence in Semantic Digital Twins: An Interactive Decision-Support System for Indoor Comfort. 2nd Annual International Conference on Digital Twins and Parallel Intelligence.

**Donkers, A.**, Yang, D., de Vries, B., Baken, N. (2022). Semantic Web Technologies for Indoor Environmental Quality: A Review and Ontology Design. Buildings. 12(10), 1522.

**Donkers, A.**, de Vries, B., & Yang, D. (2022). Knowledge Discovery Approach to Understand Occupant Experience in Cross-Domain Semantic Digital Twins. In: P. Pauwels, M. Poveda-Villalón, & W. Terkaj (editors), Proceedings of the 10th Linked Data in Architecture and Construction Workshop, co-located with 19th European Semantic Web Conference (ESWC 2022) (p. 77-86).

Li, X., Yang, D., Yuan, J., **Donkers, A.** & Liu, X. (2022). BIM-enabled semantic web for automated safety checks in subway construction. Automation in Construction, 141, 104454.

**Donkers, A.**, Yang, D., de Vries, B., & Baken, N. H. G. (2021). Real-time building performance monitoring using semantic digital twins. In M. Poveda-Villalón, & P. Pauwels (editors), LDAC 2021 Linked Data in Architecture and Construction: Proceedings of the 9th Linked Data in Architecture and Construction Workshop (p. 55-66). (CEUR Workshop Proceedings; Vol. 3081). CEUR-WS.org.

**Donkers, A.**, Yang, D., & Viktorovic, M. (2020). Influence of driving style, infrastructure, weather and traffic on electric vehicle performance. Transportation Research Part D: Transport and Environment, 88, [102569].

**Donkers, A.**, Yang, D., & Baken, N. H. G. (2020). Linked Data for Smart Homes: Comparing RDF and Labeled Property Graphs. In M. Poveda-Villalón, A. Roxin, K. McGlinn, & P. Pauwels (editors), LDAC 2020 Linked Data in Architecture and Construction: Proceedings of the 8th Linked Data in Architecture and Construction Workshop Dublin, Ireland, June 17-19, 2020 (p. 23-36). (CEUR Workshop Proceedings; Vol. 2636). CEUR-WS.org.

**Donkers, A.**, Yang, D. & Viktorovic, M. (2020). Assessing battery electric vehicle energy consumption performance: the effects of driving style, road infrastructure, weather and traffic intensity. Transportation Research Board 99th Annual Meeting, Washington D.C.

**Donkers, A.**, Quee, J., & de Vries, L. (2020). De invloed van de stedelijke omgeving en routekeuze op de actieradius van elektrische voertuigen. Tijdschrift Vervoerswetenschap, 2020-3.

**Donkers, A.**, Quee, J.G. & De Vries, L.O. (2019). Het gebruik van stedelijke data om de actieradius en routekeuze van elektrische voortuigen te optimaliseren. Colloquium Vervoersplanologisch Speurwerk, Leuven.

# **Educational activities**

### **Engineering Doctorate Projects**

2021-2023 Sander de Meij 2021-2023 Farshad Hasanabadi 2021-2023 Giel Oosterbos

#### **Master Graduation Projects**

2022 Chiel van der Pas2022 Jelle van Midden2022 Sara Guendouz

2022-2023 Systems Engineering

Guest lecture

2022-2023 Research and Development

Tutor

2021-2022 TIAS Business School

Lecturer

2021-2022 Research and Development

Tutor

2021-2022 Smart & Healthy Urban Environments

**Teaching Assistant** 

2019-2020 **Smart Cities** 

Tutor

2019-2020 Smart Urban Environments

Teaching Assistant

2017-2019 **BAU studio** 

Teaching Assistant

## Academic activities and affiliations

2023 HackMyCity Johannesburg

Lecturer

2023-now IEEE

Member

2021 AEC Hackathon Copenhagen

**Participant** 

2023 **LDAC2023** 

Organisation

2023 **SSoLDAC2023** 

Organisation

2022 **LDAC2022** 

Program Committee Member

2020-now **W3C LBD CG** 

Member

2020 **EWGT2020** 

Reviewer

2016 Shifting Perspectives Congress

Organizer

2015 Renovation & Transformation Symposium

Organizer

2015 CHEOPSx Debate Evenings

Co-founder

2014 Study trip to Berlin

Organizer

# **Presentations**

21-09-2022 EAISI Community Day

Do you ever get distracted at work?

29-06-2022 LDAC2022 Hersonissos

Knowledge Discovery Approach to Understand Occupant Experience in Cross-Domain Semantic Digital Twins

#### 11-10-2021 LDAC2021 Belval

Real-Time Building Performance Modeling using Semantic Digital Twins

#### 16-11-2020 Digital Twin Event KPN

Digital Twins Everywhere

### 17-06-2020 LDAC2020 Dublin

Linked Data for Smart Homes: Comparing RDF and Labeled Property Graphs

#### 05-02-2020 Tilburg University

Smart Cities symposium Tilburg

#### 22-11-2019 CVS Leuven

Business meets innovation event

### 16-05-2017 **Dutch Technology Week Eindhoven**

Business meets innovation event

#### 30-04-2017 Solar Decathlon Dubai

1st International Workshop for Solar Decathlon Middle East Dubai

# **Awards**

#### 2022 **LDAC2022**

Best paper award

#### 2020 Eindhoven University of Technology

Best MSc thesis of the faculty of the Built Environment

#### 2018 AnArchi Architecture Award

"Praised for the subtle use of colors and strong composition of an imaginary project called "Mapourika Observation Tower" won the Jury Prize awarded by A2 Studio."

### **2016 24:UP Antwerp**

Runner up

# Open science projects

#### **Building Performance Ontology**

https://w3id.org/bop

## **Occupant Feedback Ontology**

https://w3id.org/ofo

#### **Occupant Property Taxonomy**

https://www.github.com/AlexDonkers/opt

## **Building Assessment Ontology**

https://alexdonkers.github.io/bao

## **Open Family Home**

https://www.github.com/AlexDonkers/OpenFamilyHome

#### **Open Flat**

## https://www.github.com/AlexDonkers/OpenFlat

### **Open Smart Home**

https://www.github.com/AlexDonkers/OpenSmartHome

# **Explored**

Johannesburg, Pretoria

Lima, Huaraz, Paracas, Huacachina, Arequipa, Cuzco

Willemstad

Nice, Monaco, Èze, Arles, Montpellier, Perpignan, Dijon

Montreal, Toronto, Ottawa Serekunda, Banjul, Tendaba

Réserve de Fathala

Bangkok, Chiang Mai, Pai, Surat Thani, Koh Pha-ngan, Khao Sok

Edinburgh

Luxembourg, Belval

Dubai

Copenhagen

Berlin, Cologne, Aachen

Kraków Rome

Barcelona, Valencia

Prague

Pula, Rovinj, Poreč Bruges, Leuven, Hasselt

Bulgaria, Portugal, Greece, Turkey

**South-Africa** 

Peru
Curacao
France
Canada
Gambia
Senegal
Thailand
Scotland
Luxembourg

UAE Denmark Germany Poland Italy Spain

**Czech Republic** 

Croatia Belgium